Omer Muneer

Pakistan



oomer@altmails.com



+92 321 5335022



linkedin.com/in/omer-11

Summary

Familiar with basic sys, net & web sec with a hue of ux & ui and a pint of crms, however currently looking forward to completion of my bachelors in Computer Science.

Touched marketing, support and content editing earlier on and now I'm open for demo-work, freelance, internship & similar opportunities.

Especially if its focused around areas of my interest, or the well-being of others. or video games and food.. why not.

I completed O/Alevels at Beaconhouse & Roots. Cried hello world about 21yrs ago & ever since loved everything related to tech, especially dev, Cyber Security, ioT, Ai, & graphics. I'm also fond of blockchain, trading, and.. apparently Art as well?

Currently I'm pursuing my Bachelors in CS, so don't get a lot of work besides curriculum therefore I'm almost always available for a cup of coffee, & work opportunities, except the weekends im working on a project.

Got some expertise in vb, python, js, html, php, c++, server management & network security. Area of interest is Digital forensics, but area of basic expertise is in data recovery, graphics, development, editing, writing, marketing, security penetration testing, server software & hardware maintenance & other tech related stuff which you may see in further detail in the skill's section.

Currently I'm trying to practice with python for OSCP & CCNA and at the same time trying to be financially independent.

In the line of my work; I aim to employ simple yet effective methods of design & compliant strategies by working for a professional entity or a worthwhile purpose; with utmost zeal and zest of my soul and abilities. I try to improvise without loosing versatility; making the best of what's available for everyone to benefit, by learning, teaching and ethically using available resources in an extensive yet sustainable manner.

Since we're all here for Computer Security and.. like all fields of professionalism; I believe what matters is our intentions. Being an Ethical Hacker; just allows me to have a closer look at how Computers Work & How We Can Work together to make businesses systematically deploy computers & tech in a safe and efficient manner.

Experience

Junior Web Developer

Unique Links - Web hosting in Pakistan

Dec 2017 - Aug 2020 (2 years 9 months)

Technical

- >. Wordpress Installations,
- >. SSL Integration, (LetsEncrypt)
- >. SMS System Integration via (Cpanel)
- >. Phishing Mitigation. (Client and Email)

I miss those days; where learning & work were going along-side with unanticipated enthusiasm & boredom seemed to be a myth.

Customer Care Representative

Unique Links - Web hosting in Pakistan

Nov 2014 - Apr 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Internship related to Web-Hosting & Customer Support.

Support

- >. Customer Support (Calls & Sms)
- >. Sales Cold Calling.
- >. Invoice Management, (WHMCS)

Education



Olevel GCSE - CIE, Pre-Engineering

2005 - 2018

- >. Hands on Experience with iot dev at LearnoBots Nust
- >. House Captain & other student council admin.
- >. Organized Science & Nature Carnival Event(s)...
- >. NR3C National Cyber Scout for Cyber Awareness.
- Familiarized with Lots of Ethical; Phishing & Virus distribution Practices.

Roots IVY International

Alevel GCSE - CAIE, Pre-Engineering

2018 - 2019

Besides studies..

- >. Posters & Banners in Adobe Photoshop and illustrator for multiple events & stalls.
- Basically I knew Photoshop, but I learnt illustrator as well.
- >. Exposure to Printing, Sales, Ethics, & Interpersonal Communication skills.

The Zaheer Accademy

Alevel GCSE - CAIE, Pre-Engineering

2019 - 2021

- >. Practiced python, vb, batch & bash scripting for simple automation.
- >. Video Compression & Cloud File Management.
- >. Implemented Various work strategies to understand pro's & cons of remote & on-site work ethics.

Licenses & Certifications

Basic C++ Programming Certification - CodeAcademy

📚 S.T.E.A.M Level - 1 - LearnOBots

Skills

Social Media Marketing • Photoshop • WordPress • Video Editing • Network Security • Microsoft Office • Illustrator • Arduino • C++ • JavaScript

Honors & Awards



Best Sound & Dramatic effects - Pakistan National Council of Arts

I can manage mainstream digital and analogue audio & signal systems and have basic knowledge of related synchronized peripherals and their compatible configurations.



1st position National Computer Contest GSEA - GSEA - national computer contest (Global System Educational Assessment)

May 2015

2nd position across Pakistan.

400 students participated.

25000 students were eligible.